♪In the face of turmoil♪
♪面对混乱♪
♪Your roots hold firmly♪
♪你的根牢牢地扎根♪
♪To this piece of land♪
♪为了这片土地♪
♪Chasing after the waves♪
♪追逐海浪♪
♪My leaves flutter across♪
♪我的树叶飘舞♪
♪The horizon♪
♪地平线♪
♪Gazing from afar♪
♪远远眺望♪
♪At the end of the world♪
♪世界的尽头♪
♪Is eternity♪
♪是永恒♪
♪When we meet and then part♪
♪当我们相遇又分离♪
♪When we rely on each other and then drift apart♪
♪当我们互相依赖 然后渐行渐远♪
♪I have never forgotten♪
♪我从未忘记♪
♪As the glinting of swords cut♪
♪剑刃闪烁♪
♪Through the mottled sky♪
♪穿过斑驳的天空♪
♪The falling dreams♪
♪坠落的梦想♪
♪Shatter in the wind♪
♪随风破碎♪
♪As the wind breaks through the waves♪
♪当风破浪时♪
♪It watches thousands of sails cross♪
♪它看着万千帆影交叉♪
♪The vast land and the boundless sea♪
♪广阔的土地和无边的海洋♪
♪Armor and red robes flying high♪
♪铠甲与红袍飞扬♪
♪In the face of bitterness, intense emotions, and joyful adventure♪
♪面对辛酸、 强烈的情感、愉快的冒险♪
♪I only wish you to be by my side♪
♪我只希望你能在我身边♪
♪Making the most of what life offers♪
♪充分利用生活所提供的一切♪
♪Like towering trees with interconnected roots, I'll accompany you to the ends♪
♪就像根相连的参天大树一样 ，我会陪你走到尽头♪
♪Watching fireflies land on our shoulders♪
♪看着萤火虫落在 我们的肩上♪
♪No regrets, no doubts in this world♪
♪这个世界没有遗憾，没有怀疑♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=爱的仙境=
=Episode 16=
=第16集=
Li Ni didn't enter Luoyang City with his troops.
李泥并没有带兵进入洛阳城。
Instead, they set up camp.
相反，他们扎营了。
Why do you think they did so?
你认为他们为什么这样做？
According to the fold
根据折叠
that Li Ni had sent to Father,
李妮寄给父亲的，
it was inconvenient for the army to enter the city.
军队进城不便。
He set up camp outside
他在外面扎营
so that it's easier to conduct military operations.
以便更容易进行 军事行动。
It's obvious that he suffered defeat and wasn't willing to enter the city.
显然他已经败了 ，不愿意进城了。
He still dared to submit a fold to Father
他竟然还敢向父亲提交折子
saying that he wanted to reclaim Xichang.
说要 收复西昌。
Jun,
君，
Young Master Cui is dead.
崔少爷死了。
Cui Yi must be enraged by now.
崔毅现在肯定生气了。
It's good that he's outside the city.
还好他在城外。
If not,
如果不，
Luoyang City will be implicated
洛阳市将受到牵连
when the Cui Army arrives.
当崔军到来时。
(To Uncle)
（对叔叔）
Father, since His Highness had sent you a letter,
父亲，既然殿下 给您写了一封信，
I assume he found a way
我认为他找到了办法
to conquer Xichang.
to conquer Xichang.
In the letter, Li Ni hoped
李妮在信中希望
that I could
我可以
contact the old subjects of the previous rule
联系上一条规则的老科目
and spread the news of Sun Jing's failed conquest
并散布孙敬征伐失败的消息
in Baiyue.
in Baiyue.
He wanted the people to think
他希望人们思考
that Sun Jing suffered a major defeat.
孙敬惨败。
It's best if it causes a hike in food prices.
如果它导致食品价格上涨，那就最好了。
This way, people's hearts will be shaken.
这样一来，人们的心 就会受到震动。
Father,
父亲，
what do you think His Highness is up to?
你认为殿下在做什么？
He's crafty and adaptable to change.
他很狡猾并且能够适应变化。
I can't tell either.
我也说不清楚。
However,
然而，
it seems that he intends to cause chaos in the city.
看来他是有意要 在城里制造混乱。
He'll get his opportunity
他会得到他的机会
when the city is in chaos.
当城市陷入混乱时。
♪Reminiscing about that first moment♪
♪回忆起最初的时刻♪
♪Waiting for my inner scars to heal♪
♪等待内心的伤痕痊愈♪
♪Holding the lone spark of the opposite shore♪
♪握着对岸孤独的火花♪
♪Dwelling on your existence♪
♪铭记你的存在♪
♪My heart longs for you♪
♪我的心渴望你♪
♪It still beats for you after you break it♪
♪你打破它之后，它仍然为你跳动♪
♪I still remember our past♪
♪我还记得我们的过去♪
♪I turned around and glanced at you♪
♪我回头看了你一眼♪
♪It's hard to part with you♪
♪与你分离很难受♪
♪I once loved because of you♪
♪我曾经因为你而爱过♪
♪If only I could cherish this momentary warmth♪
♪如果能珍惜 这一刻的温暖就好了♪
Thank you.
谢谢。
It doesn't hurt, right?
不疼吧？
No.
不。
♪If only I could live this moment for you♪
♪如果我能 为你度过这一刻就好了♪
♪My memory sinks, and my heart broken♪
♪我的记忆沉沦，我的心破碎♪
♪Life and death mean nothing♪
♪生与死没有任何意义♪
♪If only I could return to your side♪
♪如果我能回到你身边就好了♪
♪Stopping by beside you♪
♪停在你身边♪
♪It's hard to part with you♪
♪与你分离很难受♪
♪I once loved because of you♪
♪我曾经因为你而爱过♪
♪If only I could cherish this momentary warmth♪
♪如果能珍惜 这一刻的温暖就好了♪
♪If only I could live this moment for you♪
♪如果我能 为你度过这一刻就好了♪
♪My memory sinks, and my heart broken♪
♪我的记忆沉沦，我的心破碎♪
♪Life and death mean nothing♪
♪生与死没有任何意义♪
♪If only I could return to your side♪
♪如果我能回到你身边就好了♪
♪Stopping by beside you♪
♪停在你身边♪
You want to play chess?
你想下棋吗？
I can get you a new set.
我可以给你买一套新的。
Why are you going through all this effort just to make them yourself?
为什么你要花这么多 精力来自己制作它们？
Young Master loved playing chess.
少爷喜欢下棋。
I once promised him
我曾经答应过他
that I would make him
我会让他
a set of chess pieces.
一组棋子。
Ying,
英，
Father finally promised us
父亲终于答应我们了
that we could lead an army and leave Yingzhou.
说我们可以率军 出营州了。
Opportunities slip away quickly.
机会很快就溜走了。
We mustn't miss out on this opportunity.
我们一定不能错过这个机会。
Really?
真的吗？
Ying,
英，
I know.
我知道。
This is what you always desired.
这就是你一直渴望的。
Ever since Sun Jing started a revolt,
自从孙敬造反后
you wanted to
你想要
vie for the world
争夺世界
and dominate the realm.
并主宰领域。
Young Master,
少爷，
you do know me well.
你确实很了解我。
Ying, your goal
莹，你的目标
is my goal.
是我的目标。
As long as there's something you wish to achieve,
只要有 自己想要实现的目标，
I'll definitely do my best
我一定会竭尽全力
to help you achieve it.
帮助您实现这一目标。
(Thank you, Young Master.)
（谢谢少爷。）
(Since I've fulfilled my end of the bargain,)
（既然我已经履行了 我的诺言，）
(you should remember)
（你应该记住）
your end of the bargain too.
你也结束了讨价还价。
Of course I do.
我当然是了。
Young Master,
少爷，
you wanted a set of chess pieces.
你想要 一套棋子。
Young Master, don't worry.
少爷，别担心。
I'll definitely make you an entire set
我一定会给你做一整套
when I have free time
当我有空的时候
out there.
在那里。
That's unnecessary.
那是不必要的。
I just need you to select the jade pieces personally.
我只是需要你 亲自挑选玉石而已。
It's the same when I tell the jade craftsman
跟玉匠说的也是一样
to make it for me.
为我做的。
That won't do.
那不行。
I must make them myself.
我必须自己做。
They represent my sincerity.
它们代表了我的诚意。
But now,
但现在，
I'm afraid I have no chance
恐怕我没有机会了
to give it to him myself.
亲自送给他。
For my sake,
为了我的缘故，
Young Master took the shot and fell into the river.
少爷中枪 ，掉进河里。
I can't even recover his body.
我什至无法恢复他的身体。
Now,
现在，
I can only erect a tomb for him
我只能为他立一座坟墓
and make him a set of chess pieces
并给他制作了一套棋子
as a burial gift.
作为丧礼。
What?
什么？
Can't I even do that now?
我现在连这个都做不到吗？
Must you say such hurtful words?
有必要说这么伤人的话吗？
Hurtful?
伤人吗？
Young Master died for my sake.
少爷为了我而死。
Shouldn't I grieve his loss?
我不应该为他的去世而悲伤吗？
Shouldn't I be upset that he's gone?
他走了我不应该感到难过吗？
So, you're still blaming me for not saving your young master, right?
所以，你还在怪我 没有救你少爷是吗？
That's right!
这是正确的！
So, you're heartbroken,
于是，你心碎了，
and you wish that you could die with him, right?
你希望能和 他一起死，对吗？
That's right!
这是正确的！
Li Ni,
李妮,
listen up.
听好了。
I was lying to you all along.
我一直在骗你。
I fell for
我爱上了
Young Master long ago.
少爷很久以前了。
I was lying to you from the start.
我从一开始就在骗你。
I was the one who duped you
是我骗了你
into heading to Xichang.
前往西昌。
As for the incident in Tong Pass,
至于潼关事件，
I plotted that
我策划了
with Young Master long ago.
很久以前就和少爷在一起了。
I did so to trick you.
我这样做是为了欺骗你。
I wanted to trick you so that you would suffer a major defeat.
我就是想骗你 ，让你惨败。
But now, Young Master is dead.
但现在，少爷死了。
I've lost all hope.
我已经失去了所有的希望。
I don't want to deceive you anymore!
我不想再欺骗你了！
Come on.
快点。
Just kill me!
杀了我吧！
You truly know
你确实知道
how to break my heart.
如何伤我的心。
That's why you said that to me.
这就是你对我这么说的原因。
I know I maligned you
我知道我诽谤你
and broke your heart.
伤了你的心。
That's why you're saying that to break my heart.
这就是为什么你这么说是 为了伤我的心。
Am I right?
我对吗？
I'm heartbroken?
我心碎了？
Why should I be heartbroken?
我何必伤心呢？
I was lying to you all along.
我一直在骗你。
I was lying to you.
我在骗你。
I never fancied you.
我从来没有喜欢过你。
Everything was fake.
一切都是假的。
But my feelings for you are true.
但我对你的感情是真的。
I don't care if you fancy your young master or not.
我不管你喜不喜欢 你少爷。
I have genuine feelings for you.
我对你有真挚的感情。
When I first met you,
当我第一次见到你时，
you kicked me into the well.
你把我踢进井里了。
Back then, I thought
那时我想
that I must get back
我必须回来
at the person
在那个人
who kicked me into the well.
谁把我踢进井里的。
But after that, we met again.
但在那之后，我们又见面了。
Initially, I could seek revenge against you.
本来，我是想报复你的。
But I didn't do so.
但我没有这样做。
I hesitated.
我犹豫了。
I didn't know why either.
我也不知道为什么。
When we were in Taiqing Palace,
我们在太清宫的时候，
I made a bet with you.
我和你打赌。
In the end, I lost to you.
最后，我还是输给了你。
But in my heart...
但在我心里...
In my heart,
在我心里，
there was an indescribable happiness.
有一种难以形容的幸福。
It's because I finally know
因为我终于知道了
that you fancy me too.
你也喜欢我。
You had feelings for me too.
你对我也有感情。
So, when you said that you were lying to me,
所以，当你说 你在骗我时，
that you didn't fancy me,
说明你不喜欢我
that everything in the past was fake,
过去的一切都是假的
I would never believe in them.
我永远不会相信他们。
It's because
这是因为
your feelings for me are true.
你对我的感情是真实的。
No matter how angry you are at me,
不管你对我有多生气
don't take it out on your body.
不要把它带在身上。
You're injured.
你受伤了。
Remember to take your medicine.
记得吃药。
Don't skip your meals.
不要不吃饭。
Why isn't it sprouting yet?
怎么还没发芽？
Could it be that the weather is too cold?
难道是 天气太冷了？
Taozi!
Taozi!
Long time no see.
好久不见。
We've finally met again.
我们终于又见面了。
Taozi.
Taozi.
Taozi, why are you ignoring me again?
桃子，你怎么又不理我了？
Let me help you out.
让我来帮你吧。
Taozi?
Taozi?
(Milk Candy) Seems like that mouse was here again.
（奶糖） 看来那只老鼠又来了。
You throw a tantrum
你发脾气
whenever he's here.
每当他在这里的时候。
One's liver suffers whenever one throws a tantrum.
每当一个人发脾气时，肝脏就会受到损害。
I'm worried that your injury
我担心你受伤
might never heal, you know?
可能永远无法痊愈，你知道吗？
Since you feel terrible,
既然你感觉很糟糕，
why don't you have some milk candy?
你为什么不吃点奶糖呢？
That mouse is something else.
那只老鼠是另一回事。
He knew that you would be furious
他知道你会生气
when you see him.
当你看到他的时候。
How dare he deliver the candy here?
他怎么敢在这里送糖果？
Why don't you take your medicine?
你为什么不吃药呢？
What's wrong with your hands?
你的手怎么了？
It's nothing. It's just some scratches.
没什么。这只是一些划痕。
Why did you do that?
你为什么这么做？
Even if Young Master is no longer with us now,
就算 现在少爷已经不在了，
I'm sure he'll be heartbroken when he sees you
我相信他 看到你的时候一定会心碎
in this state from above.
在这种状态下从上面看。
Here.
这里。
Did you
你是否
argue with Li Ni just now?
刚才和李妮吵架了？
That's right.
这是正确的。
I told him off.
我告诉他了。
I said something mean to him.
我对他说了一些难听的话。
But I didn't expect him
但我没想到他
to...
到...
What is it?
它是什么？
It's nothing.
没什么。
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
I know you're still angry
我知道你还在生气
that Li Ni didn't trust you.
李妮不信任你。
You're angry that he did nothing when we were in danger.
你很生气，因为他 在我们遇到危险时什么也没做。
You feel heartbroken and guilty
你感到心碎和内疚
about Young Master's death.
关于少爷的死。
But you can't just
但你不能只是
keep this up.
坚持下去。
You have to take care of your health too,
你也要照顾好自己的健康
am I right?
我对吗？
I got it. Don't worry about me.
我得到了它。别担心我。
We're stuck here.
我们被困在这里了。
I'm sure Great General Cui Yi
我确信崔毅大将军
is worried about us.
很担心我们。
We have to think of a way
我们得想办法
to escape to Yingzhou.
逃往瀛州。
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
why don't we
我们为什么不
start with Li Ni?
从李妮开始？
Take advantage of him to escape to Yingzhou.
趁他 逃往瀛州。
The little mouse wants to steal some lamp oil.
小老鼠想偷 一些灯油。
He failed. Thus, he tried to steal some honey.
他失败了。因此，他试图 偷一些蜂蜜。
You only took your medicine
你只吃了你的药
without taking dinner.
不吃晚饭。
If you keep this up, your health will be affected.
如果继续这样下去， 你的健康将会受到影响。
I brought you a bottle of honey.
我给你带了一瓶蜂蜜。
I made you a flatbread too.
我还给你做了个馒头。
Why don't you have some?
你为什么没有一些？
Your Highness, thanks for your concern.
殿下，谢谢您的关心。
But I'm not hungry.
但我不饿。
Even if you're mad at me,
即使你生我的气
you can't just starve yourself.
你不能让自己挨饿。
Your Highness, why are you so concerned about a prisoner like me?
殿下，为何如此关心 我这样的囚犯？
It's late now.
现在已经很晚了。
I'm a woman while you're a man.
我是女人，而你是男人。
It's inappropriate for you to be here.
你来这里不合适。
You should leave.
你应该离开。
I just want you
我只是要你
to stay here for a few more days.
在这里多住几天。
You're not a prisoner.
你不是囚犯。
Your Highness, you don't need to make up such a grand excuse.
殿下，您不需要 编出这么冠冕堂皇的借口。
Young Master is dead.
少爷死了。
I'm just a woman.
我只是一个女人。
You can't use me
你不能使用我
to coerce the Cui Army
胁迫崔军
to do your bidding.
执行你的命令。
Since you said I wasn't a prisoner,
既然你说我不是囚犯
why aren't you willing to release me?
你为什么不愿意释放我？
It's because you're injured.
那是因为你受伤了。
I would've died anyway
无论如何我都会死
had you arrived one second later.
你晚一秒钟才到吗？
There's no need for you to be concerned about my injury.
我的伤势你不用担心。
Even if you're not doing it for me,
即使你不是为了我做这件事
you should do it for Taozi's sake.
为了桃子，你应该这样做。
She's anxious about
她很着急
your condition every day.
你每天的状况。
You're not taking your medicine nor meals.
你没有吃药，也没有吃饭。
If this continues, your health will be affected.
如果这种情况持续下去， 您的健康将会受到影响。
Don't try to blackmail me
不要试图勒索我
with the people beside me.
和我身边的人。
Taozi and I are like sisters.
我和桃子就像姐妹一样。
We know each other's conditions
我们了解彼此的条件
the best.
最好的。
It has nothing to do with you.
这与你无关。
Since you're still mad at me,
既然你还在生我的气
I'll leave first.
我先走了。
Don't sleep with anger, okay?
别带着怒气睡觉好吗？
It's bad for your health.
这对你的健康有害。
Taozi!
Taozi!
Taozi.
Taozi.
Let me carry it for you.
让我帮你拿吧。
Taozi,
Taozi,
are you still angry at me?
你还在生我的气吗？
Can you please talk to me?
你能和我谈谈吗？
Taozi, are you going to gather herbs?
桃子，你要去采药吗？
Let me tag along.
让我跟着去吧。
Taozi.
Taozi.
His Majesty conferred me the title of Lord Qin,
陛下封我 为秦王，
appointed me as Commander-in-Chief,
任命我为总司令
and ordered me to reclaim Xichang?
还命令我收复西昌？
The imperial edict arrived here last night.
圣旨 昨晚抵达这里。
Not only did he confer the title of Lord Qin to you,
他不但封 你为秦王，
but he also conferred the titles of Lord Qi and Lord Xin
但他还封 齐公、辛公。
to Lord Kuaiji and Lord Linzi respectively.
分别为会稽君、 临子君。
They're putting me on open fire here.
他们在这里向我开火。
If I fail to reclaim Xichang,
如果我不能收复西昌
I'll be punished, huh?
我会受到惩罚吧？
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
why don't you refuse it?
你为什么不拒绝呢？
Refuse what?
拒绝什么？
Since His Majesty already issued an edict,
既然陛下已经 下了圣旨，
I'll be Lord Qin then.
以后我就是秦王了。
Now,
现在，
as the Commander-in-Chief,
作为总司令，
I can dispatch the loyalists
我可以派遣忠诚者
officially
正式
to reclaim Xichang.
收复西昌。
This time, I'll leave the city to you guys.
这一次，我就把这座城市留给你们了。
Don't worry, Mister Shiqi.
别担心，士奇先生。
We'll definitely follow your instructions
我们一定会按照 您的指示进行
and flip Xichang
并翻转西昌
upside down.
倒挂。
Precisely.
恰恰。
We might not be good at other things,
我们可能不擅长其他事情，
but flipping places upside down
但颠倒了地方
is our expertise.
是我们的专长。
It's a shame that I haven't fully recovered yet.
可惜 我还没有完全康复。
I can't join you guys this time.
这次我不能和你们一起了。
I'll go ahead
我会继续
and do your share for you.
并为你尽你的一份力量。
There's an undercurrent surging.
有一股暗流涌动。
We can't tell friends from foes.
我们无法区分朋友和敌人。
You guys must be careful.
你们一定要小心。
Must act cautiously.
必须谨慎行事。
And, you must ensure your own safety.
而且，你必须确保自己的安全。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
Once we take down Xichang,
一旦我们拿下了西昌
we'll come back and drink with you.
我们会回来和你一起喝酒。
Let's drink!
我们喝吧！
We'll conquer Xichang and drink together when we're back!
回来我们一起征服西昌，一起喝酒！
Let's drink together!
我们一起喝吧！
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Prime Minister Gu,
尊敬的顾总理，
wild rumors have been spreading in the city.
城里流传着疯狂的谣言。
There's a hike in food prices,
食品价格上涨，
and the people are panicking.
人们很恐慌。
They say that the army Grand Governor
他们说陆军 大总督
had sent to conquer Baiyue suffered a major defeat.
曾派人征讨百越， 遭遇重大失败。
They were also saying
他们还说
that Li Ni, the son of the fake emperor, was conferred the title of Lord Qin.
假皇帝之子李尼 被封为秦王。
And now, he's going to attack Xichang.
而现在，他要攻打西昌。
People say that he was born
人们说他出生了
to jinx Grand Governor.
到金克丝大总督。
What else did you hear?
你还听到了什么？
They even said Lord Qin sent his spies here
还说秦王 派了探子来这里
to poison the well water.
毒害井水。
People are panicking.
人们很恐慌。
They dare not consume well water anymore.
他们不敢再喝 井水了。
Some even said
甚至有人说
that the granary was empty.
粮仓是空的。
There was no food inside.
里面没有食物。
They said
他们说
the army that was sent to Baiyue
派往百越的军队
had already taken all of them.
已经全部拿走了。
Once...
一次...
Once Lord Qin surrounds our city,
一旦秦王包围了我们的城市，
the people in the city
城里的人
will starve to death.
会饿死的。
All right. I understand. You may leave.
好的。我明白。你可以离开了。
Order our servants to guard the door. Don't let anyone out.
吩咐仆人守门。 不要让任何人出去。
Yes, Prime Minister.
是的，总理。
Do you understand now?
你现在明白了么？
Is Lord Qin trying to cause a ruckus here?
秦王这是要 在这里闹事吗？
That's right.
这是正确的。
Lord Qin wants to sow discord among the people.
秦王想要挑拨 民间。
Now, let's see what the person inside the palace will do
现在，看看 宫里的人会做什么
to deal with this situation.
来应对这种情况。
Capture all those who were spreading the rumors
抓捕所有 散布谣言的人
and kill them.
并杀死他们。
Grand Governor,
大总督，
I'm afraid the rumor-spreaders have an ulterior motive.
恐怕造谣者 别有用心。
That's why we have to kill them.
这就是为什么我们必须杀死他们。
Not only will I kill them,
我不但要杀了他们，
but I'll also exterminate their families and clans.
但我也会消灭 他们的家人和氏族。
I'll see
我会明白的
who's daring enough
谁够大胆
to do something like this after this.
在此之后做类似的事情。
Yes, Grand Governor.
是的，大总督。
Why are you so early today?
你今天怎么这么早？
You didn't like to use rouge in the past.
以前你不喜欢用胭脂。
What's with the sudden fondness?
突然的喜欢是怎么回事？
Maybe it was because of
也许是因为
the white hair
白头发
I saw in the mirror that day.
那天我在镜子里看到了。
Jing,
静,
are you troubled by court affairs?
您是否因法庭事务而烦恼？
You don't need to tell me about them.
你不需要告诉我他们的事。
Let's go and take a walk.
我们去散步吧。
Ever since I took up arms,
自从我拿起武器
I always thought
我一直以为
that the world
那个世界
could be conquered easily.
可以轻易被征服。
I never expected
我万万没想到
Li Ni to lead the Zhenxi Army
Li Ni to lead the Zhenxi Army
all the way here.
一直到这里。
He's targeting Xichang now.
他现在的目标是西昌。
Tong Pass is the gate to the two capitals.
潼关是 两都的门户。
As long as we own Tong Pass,
只要我们拥有通关，
it's useless even if
即使
Li Ni owns Luoyang.
Li Ni owns Luoyang.
Cui Yi is devious and cunning.
崔毅狡猾狡诈。
If he joins hands with Li Ni,
如果他和李妮联手，
it'll be tough for us.
这对我们来说会很困难。
That won't happen.
那不会发生。
Cui Yi has an ulterior motive.
崔毅别有用心。
If not, he wouldn't have sent his army out of Yingzhou.
不然的话，他也不会出兵 出瀛州。
Li Ni is the son of the fake emperor.
李妮是假皇帝的儿子。
They harbor different motives.
他们怀有不同的动机。
They won't join hands that easily.
他们不会那么容易牵手。
I shouldn't have told you about that.
我不应该告诉你这件事。
Come, let's play some polo.
来吧，我们来打马球吧。
Okay.
好的。
What? You plan
什么？你计划
to ignore me for the rest of your life?
一辈子都不理我吗？
Lord Qin, you're overthinking it.
秦王你想多了。
You were just conferred the title of Lord Qin.
你刚刚被封为 秦王。
There are plenty of people who wish to gain your favor.
有很多人 希望得到你的青睐。
Your Highness, you don't need to care about me.
殿下，您不必 关心我。
In the past, you call me the imperial grandson.
以前你叫我 皇孙。
Now, you call me Your Highness.
现在，您称呼我为殿下。
Aren't you willing
难道你不愿意吗
to call me Shiqi again?
又叫我诗琪吗？
This place is the best.
这个地方是最好的。
When I was young,
我小的时候，
my nanny said
我的保姆说
that I should make a bamboo dragonfly
我应该做一只竹蜻蜓
whenever I have a wish.
每当我有一个愿望时。
My wish will be granted
我的愿望将会实现
when it falls to the ground.
当它掉到地上时。
Back then,
那时，
I wanted to see my mother very badly.
我非常想见到我的母亲。
Everyone had a mother, except for me.
每个人都有母亲，除了我。
Thus,
因此，
I made plenty of bamboo dragonflies.
我做了很多竹蜻蜓。
I scaled to the top of the wall and released them one by one.
我爬到了墙顶 ，把它们一一释放了。
When I was done,
当我完成后，
I found out that my nanny was saying that just to coax me.
我发现保姆这么说 只是为了哄我。
That wish of mine
我的那个愿望
could never be fulfilled
永远无法实现
no matter how many bamboo dragonflies I made.
不管 我做了多少只竹蜻蜓。
People say
人们说
that one wouldn't repeat
那个不会重复的
their silly mistakes again.
他们又犯了愚蠢的错误。
Even so, I still made plenty of bamboo dragonflies.
尽管如此，我还是做了很多 竹蜻蜓。
Because it's you.
因为是你。
For you,
为你，
I'm willing to do all the silly things in the world.
我愿意做 世界上所有愚蠢的事情。
Ying,
英，
can you please forgive me?
你能原谅我吗？
I promise,
我保证，
from now on,
今后，
I won't misunderstand your intention.
我不会误解你的意图。
If so, you should stop trapping me here.
既然如此，你就别再把我困在这里了。
Release me and Taozi back to Yingzhou.
放我和桃子回瀛州。
I can't allow that.
我不能允许这样的事情发生。
If so,
如果是这样，
I have nothing to say to you.
我无话可说。
You're still in the mood to fish, huh?
你还有心情去钓鱼吧？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Is Cui Yi's main army here?
崔毅的主力部队在吗？
Not yet.
还没有。
They're taking their sweet time.
他们正在享受甜蜜时光。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
don't you think
你不觉得吗
Cui Yi has an ulterior motive?
崔毅别有用心？
The situation in Xichang is ever-changing.
西昌的局势 瞬息万变。
If he doesn't hurry up,
如果他不快点的话
I'm afraid we'll miss out
恐怕我们会错过
on this opportunity.
借此机会。
I coerced him into doing this.
我强迫他这样做。
Of course he's unhappy to do so.
他当然不乐意这样做。
Besides,
除了，
he has the number advantage.
他有人数优势。
But he has to try his best to conquer the city.
但他必须尽全力 征服这座城市。
Do you think he'll be willing to hurry when he's in that situation?
你认为他在这种情况下会愿意匆忙吗？
I just received news.
我刚刚收到消息。
Great General is already...
大将军已经……
This is a rare opportunity indeed.
这确实是一个难得的机会。
Maybe we can
也许我们可以
use this chance to escape.
趁这个机会逃跑。
Lieutenant He, I knew you could
何中尉，我就知道你可以
think of a great idea.
想出一个好主意。
However, we need to plan this out.
然而，我们需要对此进行计划。
Li Ni is very intelligent.
李妮非常聪明。
It's difficult for us to escape
我们很难逃脱
without a thorough plan.
没有周密的计划。
Where's Li Ni?
李妮在哪儿？
Ear has been following me all day long.
耳朵整天跟着我。
He kept yapping
他不停地叫嚷
because I ignored him.
因为我忽略了他。
He said that Li Ni was fishing by the lake
他说李妮 在湖边钓鱼
this afternoon.
今天下午。
He even asked me
他还问我
if I wanted to have some fresh fish.
如果我想吃一些新鲜的鱼。
He was fishing?
他在钓鱼？
Who's there?
谁在那儿？
Your Highness, it's me.
殿下，是我。
Taozi.
Taozi.
Please come in.
请进来。
Your Highness, General Pei Yuan.
裴渊将军殿下。
Your Highness,
殿下，
Lieutenant He was taking medicine every day.
何中尉 每天都在吃药。
She didn't take much food either.
她也没有吃太多食物。
She has lost a lot of weight.
她瘦了很多。
You knew that too.
你也知道这一点。
After she took her medicine,
她服药后，
she suddenly said she wanted to have fish ball soup.
她突然说 她想喝鱼丸汤。
I asked the kitchen about it.
我向厨房询问了此事。
But they said the marketplace was closed today.
但他们说市场 今天关闭。
They only bought some vegetables.
他们只买了一些蔬菜。
Coincidentally,
无独有偶，
I saw some fish
我看到了一些鱼
in the bucket.
在桶里。
But they said
但他们说
those were the fish
这些就是鱼
you caught by the lake today.
你今天在湖边被抓到了。
I dare not use them without your permission.
未经你的允许我不敢使用它们。
That's why I came here to ask for your permission.
这就是为什么我来这里 寻求你的许可。
Finally she has an appetite,
终于有胃口了
I'll make the fish ball soup.
我来做鱼丸汤。
No need for that.
没必要这样。
I can make it.
我可以做到。
It's fine.
没关系。
It takes skills to make fish balls.
做鱼丸是需要技巧的。
Let me do it.
让我来做吧。
If that's the case,
如果是这样的话，
Your Highness, please go ahead.
殿下，请继续。
Taozi, you're back.
桃子，你回来了。
Yeah, I'm back.
是的，我回来了。
Try it while it's hot.
趁热试试吧。
It'll smell fishy when it gets cold.
冷了就会有鱼腥味。
Is it nice?
是不是不错？
It's pretty fresh.
还蛮新鲜的。
You should
你应该
rest and recuperate.
休息和恢复。
Even if you're mad at me,
即使你生我的气
you have to cherish your body.
你要珍惜你的身体。
In the future,
将来，
just tell me what you want
告诉我你想要什么
and what you wish to eat.
以及你想吃什么。
I'll get them for you.
我会帮你拿的。
Aren't you afraid that I'll use this chance
你就不怕 我利用这个机会吗
to relay a message back home
转发消息回家
and escape from this place?
并逃离这个地方？
Even if you do escape from here,
就算你真的逃离这里
I can intercept you
我可以拦截你
and bring you back.
并带你回来。
If you don't believe me,
如果你不相信我
feel free to give it a try.
请随意尝试一下。
The army Sun Jing had sent to Baiyue
孙敬派往百越的军队
didn't really suffer a defeat.
并没有真正遭受失败。
Only his army in Yingzhou suffered a defeat.
唯有颍州之军 惨败。
I'm afraid Sun Jing will recall
我怕孙静会回忆起来
his army in Baiyue.
他的军队在百越。
And, he owns Tong Pass.
而且，他还拥有通关。
You're caught in a pincer attack.
你陷入了夹击。
Unless
除非
you can conquer Xichang
you can conquer Xichang
before the army in Baiyue
百越军前
comes back.
回来。
However, I'm afraid
不过，我恐怕
the Zhenxi Army
the Zhenxi Army
is incapable of such a feat at the moment.
目前还无法做到这一点。
Excellent point.
很棒的一点。
However,
然而，
I still won't release you.
我还是不会放开你
Your Highness, you do know me well, huh?
殿下，您果然很了解我吧？
You know me well too.
你也很了解我。
We're the same.
我们是一样的。
Taozi, have you managed to buy everything you need?
桃子，你 需要的东西都买齐了吗？
That incident was so long ago.
那件事已经是很久以前的事了。
Can you please talk to me?
你能和我谈谈吗？
I'll do anything for you
我会为你做任何事
as long as you talk to me.
只要你跟我说话。
Don't you know why I'm ignoring you?
你不知道我为什么不理你吗？
Back then, you were just observing us
那时你只是观察我们
when Lieutenant He and I were under pursuit.
当我和何中尉 被追击时。
You guys ignored us.
你们无视我们。
You're just like Lord Qin.
你就像秦王爷一样。
You guys are heartless, indifferent,
你们无情、冷漠、
and cold-hearted!
并且冷酷无情！
That's not it.
不是这个。
I was anxious too.
我也很着急。
I wanted to rush down and save you.
我真想冲下去 救你。
But it was a military order. I...
但这是军事命令。我...
I had no choice.
我别无选择。
Besides,
除了，
the soldiers of the Zhenxi Army
镇西军士兵
never go against military orders.
决不违背军事命令。
Your excuses.
你的借口。
I'm not making up excuses.
我不是在编造借口。
That day,
那天，
Mister Shiqi knew what he was doing.
十七先生知道自己在做什么。
He had his bow drawn.
他拉开了弓。
He wouldn't just stand there and see you hurt.
他不会只是站在那里 看着你受伤。
Taozi.
Taozi.
What exactly do you want me to do before you'll forgive me?
在你原谅我之前，你到底想让我做什么？
Why don't I gather herbs with you
我为什么不和你一起采草药呢
or buy something nice for you?
或者给你买点好东西？
Do you want to have pig ears?
你想拥有猪耳朵吗？
I'll do anything you like as long as you stop ignoring me.
只要你不再无视我，我会做任何你喜欢的事。
Really?
真的吗？
Anything?
任何事物？
Except for releasing you and Lieutenant He.
除了释放你 和何中尉。
You have good hearing, right?
你听力很好，对吧？
Don't tell me
别告诉我
you want to have my ears?
你想拥有我的耳朵吗？
Nonsense.
废话。
Who wants to have your stupid ears?
谁想要你那双蠢耳朵？
I just
我只是
want you
想你
to make a whistle for me.
为我吹口哨。
A whistle?
口哨？
I want you to make a whistle that only you can hear.
我希望你吹出 只有你能听到的口哨。
If I need your help
如果我需要你的帮助
for any emergencies,
如有任何紧急情况，
I'll blow the whistle.
我会吹哨子。
That sounds difficult.
听起来很难。
But don't worry.
但不用担心。
I can definitely make it for you.
我绝对可以为你做。
That's more like it.
这还差不多。
So, Taozi, you'll stop ignoring me, right?
所以，桃子，你就别再无视我了吧？
You are not angry at me, right?
你没有生我的气吧？
That depends on my mood.
这取决于我的心情。
Mister Shiqi went to see Lieutenant He just now.
士奇先生刚才去见何中尉了。
She shut the door on him again.
她再次把他关上了门。
He deserved it.
他应得的。
Miss Taozi,
Miss Taozi,
actually, Mister Shiqi
事实上，世奇先生
is very nice to Lieutenant He.
对何中尉很好。
Why don't you speak up
你为什么不说话
for him in front of her
为了在她面前的他
and try to appease her?
并试图安抚她？
If he was
如果他是
truly nice to Lieutenant He,
对何中尉真的很好，
he wouldn't just use these random herbs to brew her medicine.
他不会只是用这些随意的草药 来给她熬药。
Even now, Lieutenant He hasn't recovered from her injuries.
到现在，何中尉的伤势还没有痊愈。
Look. What are these?
看。这些是什么？
Miss Taozi, don't be angry.
桃子小姐，别生气。
Well, give me the prescription.
好吧，给我处方。
I'll buy the herbs.
我去买草药。
If I can't buy them nearby,
如果附近买不到的话
I'll buy them in Xichang or Luoyang, OK?
我去西昌或者洛阳买，可以吗？
You said so yourself.
你自己也这么说。
Fine.
美好的。
I'll get you the prescription right now.
我现在就给你开药方。
Okay.
好的。
Keep fanning it. Don't stop.
继续扇它。别停下来。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Lieutenant He hasn't recovered from her injuries.
何中尉的伤势还没有恢复。
The herbs here are limited.
这里的草药是有限的。
So Miss Taozi gave me a prescription.
于是桃子小姐 给我开了一个药方。
She told me to buy these herbs.
她叫我去买这些草药。
By the way, Taozi also said
对了，桃子也说了
that she would speak up for you
她会为你说话
in front of Lieutenant He
在何中尉面前
as long as I buy all of these herbs.
只要我把这些草药都买下来。
Dragon bone,
龙骨，
Forsythia suspensa,
连翘暂停，
Aesculus hippocastanum,
七叶树
pumice, ephedra,
浮石、麻黄、
and Fritillaria pallidiflora?
还有苍白贝母？
That's a lot of herbs.
那是很多草药。
And, she even designated the stores.
而且，她还指定了商店。
The stores are far away from each other too.
商店之间的距离也很远。
Taozi said
桃子说
she knew which store sold the best herbs.
她知道哪家商店卖的草药最好。
If I try
如果我尝试
to brush her off,
把她赶走，
she won't let me off when she finds out.
她知道后不会放过我的。
Good job.
好工作。
I'll go now.
我现在就走。
Taozi didn't tell you
桃子没告诉你
to buy them one by one, right?
一件一件地买，对吗？
Isn't it faster
不是更快吗
if you get help?
如果你得到帮助？
This is a request from Miss Taozi.
这是桃子小姐的请求。
How could I tell other people to do it?
我怎么能告诉其他人这样做呢？
Besides, it's just a few stores.
此外，这只是几家商店。
I travel fast. It won't take up much time.
我旅行很快。 不会占用太多时间。
I'll be leaving now.
我现在就要走了。
(Huichun Apothecary) Huichen Apothecary? I finally found it.
（回春药师） 回尘药师？我终于找到了。
Shopkeeper,
店主，
I want to buy this.
我想要买这个东西。
Aesculus hippocastanum.
七叶树。
(Huichun Apothecary) (Aesculus hippocastanum)
（回春药师） （七叶树）
Here are your herbs.
这是你的草药。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Here's the money. Keep the change.
这是钱。留着零钱吧。
Take care.
小心。
Miss Taozi!
Miss Taozi!
I bought all the herbs.
我买了所有的草药。
That quickly?
这么快？
Did you skive and skip some of them?
你是否跳过了其中的一些内容？
I didn't!
我没有！
I bought them one by one
我一一买了
according to your list.
根据你的清单。
Let me see.
让我看看。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Miss Taozi,
Miss Taozi,
can you please
请你
speak up for Mister Shiqi
为石奇先生说话
in front of Lieutenant He then?
那么当着何中尉的面呢？
Fine.
美好的。
I'll do it on account of these herbs.
我会因为这些草药而做到这一点。
Let me check them again.
让我再检查一下。
Go ahead.
前进。
Ying.
莹。
The weather is pretty good today.
今天天气很好。
I got you some osmanthus.
我给你买了一些桂花。
Ying?
莹？
I'll leave it at your doorstep then.
那我就把它放在你家门口了。
♪If I forget the fleeting of time♪
♪如果我忘记了转瞬即逝的时光♪
♪Waiting for memories to shatter and sink♪
♪等待记忆 破碎沉没♪
♪The emotional scars in your heart♪
♪你心中的情感伤痕♪
♪Are the entanglement I find hard to let go of♪
♪是我难以释怀的纠葛吗♪
♪If longing is not forgotten♪
♪如果没有忘记渴望的话♪
♪I long to return to the very first moment♪
♪我渴望回到 最初的那一刻♪
♪The affection we had in our fateful situation♪
♪我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪How I wish to keep it for you♪
♪我多么想为你保留它♪
♪If love still remembers the promises we made♪
♪如果爱还记得 我们的约定♪
♪Despite going against fate, I have no regrets loving you♪
♪尽管违背命运， 我也不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
we have fresh flowers again today.
今天我们又收到鲜花了。
I'll swap yesterday's bouquet for this one.
我要把昨天的花束换成 这束。
Lieutenant He, you should stop being mad.
何中尉， 你别再生气了。
I think Lord Qin...
我觉得秦王...
No.
不。
I mean he's apologizing to you sincerely this time.
我的意思是，他 这次是真心实意地向你道歉的。
Didn't he say
他不是说吗
that he wasn't supposed to trust you?
他不应该信任你？
Actually, Cui Li was the one
其实崔莉就是那个
behind Young Master's passing.
少爷去世的背后。
It's not his fault.
这不是他的错。
Strange.
奇怪的。
Why are you
你为什么
speaking up for him today?
今天为他说话吗？
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
I'm doing this for your sake.
我这样做是为了你。
I think Lord Qin
我觉得秦王爷
is truly nice to you.
对你真的很好。
He even sent his men to buy herbs from various stores.
他甚至派人 去各个商店购买草药。
He still wants to keep you company here
他还想在这里陪你
even if you show him a long face
即使你给他拉长脸
every day.
每天。
Actually,
实际上，
I know that he's sincere in apologizing to me too.
我知道他也是诚心 向我道歉的。
I should stop being mad at him.
我应该停止生他的气。
I wouldn't be this angry
我不会这么生气
if someone else did this.
如果其他人这样做了。
But...
但...
To me, he's different from
对我来说，他不同于
other people.
其他人。
I see.
我懂了。
I was wondering why.
我想知道为什么。
I'll get angry if you keep that up.
如果你再这样下去我会生气的。
It's my fault.
我的错。
Don't be angry.
别生气。
I'll change your flowers for you.
我会为你换花。
Great General.
伟大的将军。
We've received news.
我们收到消息了。
(Xichang)
(西昌)
Mister Shiqi!
Mister Shiqi!
Mister Shiqi, I have good news.
士奇先生，我有个好消息。
What is it?
它是什么？
Taozi said
桃子说
she finally convinced
她终于说服了
Lieutenant He to see you
何中尉来看你
after all the effort she has put in.
经过她付出的所有努力。
Tonight, they'll hold a banquet beside the lotus pond.
今晚，他们将在荷塘边举办宴会。
By then, Taozi will act accordingly
到时候，桃子就会相应行动
and give you two a chance to speak in private.
并给你们两个 私下交谈的机会。
By the way, Taozi also said
对了，桃子也说了
that all women
那所有的女人
are soft-hearted.
都是心软的。
By then, you need to apologize to her
到时候你就得向她道歉了
sincerely.
真挚地。
This way,
这边走，
Lieutenant He can be appeased.
何中尉可以安抚了。
Thank Miss Taozi for me.
替我谢谢桃子小姐。
Okay.
好的。
♪If I forget the fleeting of time♪
♪如果我忘记了转瞬即逝的时光♪
♪Waiting for memories♪
♪等待回忆♪
♪To shatter and sink♪
♪破碎并沉没♪
♪The emotional scars in your heart♪
♪你心中的情感伤痕♪
♪Are the entanglement♪
♪是纠缠♪
♪I find hard to let go of♪
♪我发现很难放手♪
♪If longing is not forgotten♪
♪如果没有忘记渴望的话♪
♪I long to return to the very first moment♪
♪我渴望回到 最初的那一刻♪
♪The affection we had in our fateful situation♪
♪我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪How I wish to keep it for you♪
♪我多么想为你保留它♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promises we made♪
♪我们的约定♪
♪Even if this love hurts me♪
♪即使这份爱让我受伤♪
♪I'll continue living for you♪
♪我会继续为你而活♪
♪Holding onto the memories♪
♪紧紧抓住回忆♪
♪Waiting is my persistence♪
♪等待是我的坚持♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪我对你的承诺♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪尽管违背命运♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪我不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪我对你的承诺♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪尽管违背命运♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪我不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪